Steve, where are you going?
Thank you.
I'm on the screen.
Hey, thanks for coming.
I know this is the talk right before lunch,
so I'm not going to talk too much in detail.
I'm mostly going to just show demos and we'll go right into lunch that way.
So. Hello.
I'm Steve.
I'm the founder CEO of tldraw, which is a couple of different things.
It's a London based startup.
We're up in Finsbury Park.
It's also a well it's this it's
this is kind of
if you're familiar with, I don't know, Miro or Excalidraw
or these other sort of like online collaborative whiteboards
was one of those.
There's a couple of things that are a little different.
Number one, it's it's it's very good.
Number two, it's a normal website that everything that you're
looking at here, the canvas, the, the, the contents of the canvas are
essentially one big react application.
So there's no no canvas element on the canvas.
This is a this is a div and that's a div and that's an inside of a div
and things like that which I'll will be
important later
is also an SDK.
So this is how we make our money.
If you're a company building a product that wants to leverage a canvas in one way
or another.
You don't want to build all the canvas same way that you don't
want to build a whole text editor. If you need to edit text.
So you can you can license SDK to do that,
just as a kind of a quick little highlight reel.
If you've used new canvas, this is a this is our canvas. Hey.
And Luma Luma AI really really great
use of the canvas for generating images and videos, things like that.
But there are there are a lot.
If you see a cool canvas product
that's coming out in 2026, chances are it's built with us.
So part of our,
well,
part of my job, having a startup that makes an SDK that promises, hey,
you can build cool stuff with with this SDK is building cool
stuff with the SDK, kind of like demonstrating what it can do.
Over the last couple of years, a lot of those experiments have involved
AI and
well, let me show you.
Okay, so we're on we're on make real right now actually we're not on com.
So I'm going to going to skip over all this pitches.
But but it really is
I mean just to to show you it really is a normal canvas on the, on the canvas.
Like this is a, you know, a YouTube video that I can still play with
even though it's rich embedded content.
And the same way that notion kind of like
is like a document editor, but it's also just normal stuff like that.
Same thing for tldraw.
So back in 2023,
well, just gives you the framing for the rest of the talk.
It's all going to be demos from here on
Reddit, mostly demos of these,
these AI products that we've experimented with.
November 2023 GPT four with vision just launches.
This is the first time, like a really good vision
model is available via like a developer API.
That API is in preview.
You get like 30 requests
a day or something
like that, and it's ridiculously expensive,
but it's the first time that people can start playing around with products
for this.
So I don't know if if you were on Twitter
in November 2023,
you probably saw this tweet about Make Real.
And I'd say that because it was the first kind of like.
Using AI to
produce code kind of thing, to really break containment,
like kind of escape from normal, like a niche ML community
type of tweets and go really broad.
The closest thing to this that preceded it was like Carpathians,
like menu like visualizer type of app.
This, this first kind of vibe coding stuff and and yeah,
the basic idea is that you have a canvas where you can make stuff right.
You can draw diagrams and things like that, and you have an AI
that can see, let's see if we can get the AI to make the stuff that we're drawing.
Right.
So, you know, well, the models have gotten a lot
better since 2023, but the application still works.
I'll show you.
So normally you're prompting and maybe you are just using text.
And basically it's it's this right.
I want like an orange kind of device
shows a timer, zero zero buttons for start stop
ad time and and you know, models are especially these days.
This is much better than it was in 2023.
Like totally capable of working with that and adding to it and so on.
So wonderful.
I have my little timer and I used nothing but text to to get there.
But.
With Make Real you can
kind of get a similar results just with the the drawing.
Right?
Like if I took this and just copied it as a, as a screenshot
and like just pasted the screenshot into a cursor or something, said, hey,
can you make this for me then.
Then yeah, it would, it would be able to do that as well.
One of the cool things we've found about this,
and again, you have to remember 2023, right?
There was no like vibe.
Coding wasn't a word yet that came later.
There was no lovable or this whole idea of AI coding.
Well, it just hadn't arrived in the same way as as it did in 2024.
For a lot of people, this was like the first time they'd ever
created something technical at all,
because kind of the the there was no code
and they could use their existing skills, which was like drawing rectangles.
Something fun we found about something fun that we found out about.
This kind of way of using the canvas, though, is that, you know,
if I wanted to change something about just a text to to website thing,
I could probably say like, like, no, no, make it blue or,
you know, asking these kind of complex positional things
like, hey, switch the position of these buttons and so on.
But what is what is cool about this is that even though
this is a kind of a working website that has been created from.
Created from it, from an image, right?
It's sitting on the canvas.
I can kind of do these stuff like this.
I can just kind of draw on top of it.
And I could say like.
Green
and maybe make the.
You know, I don't know, do something like this.
And then in the same way that I selected all this
and click the button to make it turn into a prototype,
I can select all of this and click the button,
and it will send that new screenshot, which includes the website itself,
to the model and saying, hey, can you.
Well, all right.
Switching the buttons didn't work, but the green did.
That.
You can you can use this to kind of iterate on the the website
using annotation.
This was such a cool, cool thing to discover that that annotation
could be an input to these, these language models.
And in fact, if I close the tabs.
But if you go to some of the customers that have used the SDK now,
like like Google and Mixed borders or stitch or
Lit and Luma, whatever, runway, this idea of using annotations
as an input and part of the prompt is something that has gone.
People have taken really, really far.
So let me see how far I can push this with I don't know what model I'm using.
Gemini three flash preview.
Maybe we'll go a little bit harder.
Let me let me switch the model. By the way.
This is all bring your own token.
We haven't monetized this at all.
So you have to
have to trust me not to
steal your API token, but I won't, I promise.
Let's say we have something like this, right?
This is much more complex for me to prompt this with.
With language would be quite complex, right?
Like I want the user's camera feed.
I want to have switches for dot matrix or colors.
I want to have a control for how big the dot size is.
I want to have a little panel at the bottom with like
the thumbnails of the previous things, and
that's like, you could do it.
You could do it with supplementing both the language and
maybe Figma designs or something else.
But and make real.
The canvas is a really, really cool place to make that decision,
to have that kind of iteration loop and to have that back and forth
and like, like any good cooking show, I do have a
the emergency, you know, finished products over here.
So we'll see if it actually uses my camera here.
Otherwise we'll need to we'll need to change the prompt.
It's kind of looking like it.
It's interesting.
It kind of used the same design language as before.
As you can imagine.
It creates the markup and then it creates the
oh there we go.
Hey, that's not bad, right?
I mean, hey, all right.
Cool.
Let me see if it actually works.
So color color works.
The dot matrix that works. Hello.
Dot size. You know.
And can I capture I can
pretty cool right now.
This didn't have any.
Well I guess it had a couple of words in it, but this is just an image as input.
I got a thing as output.
And in theory I could kind of continue to to
mark it up and see if I can create later iterations and stuff like that.
So Make Real was like one of the first AI projects that we ever played with.
Right?
And this was like, oh wow, vision models.
That's that's where it's at. Right.
And we did do, do other stuff like we created this whole thing
called tldraw computer, which leveraged the canvas to do.
To do things that you could do in a chat,
but that like a chat really isn't the right user interface for.
One of the things that you can do
outside of 1D chat
thing is branching, branching conversations
as well as like multi-step prompts in a way that is like repeatable.
It's very hard to do in chat, trivial to do using kind of code
or certain workflow editors that now exist,
but but hard to be creative with, I would say.
So. The canvas is a great place to do that because you can create
these kind of directed graphs.
You can create context really dynamically.
I'm going to change this to actually use use my own drawing.
We need a need the name of a sport
we could Madlib this.
Real tennis.
Is that like real ultimate? Yeah. Or real real tennis.
All right.
Real tennis. But we need something else.
What's what's the last restaurant you went to?
I don't know the name.
What kind of food was it?
Malaysian.
Well, I don't know about this, all right.
I don't know if I can spell that.
Malaysian. Real tennis. Gotta be careful.
And I want this to be,
Kind of the logo.
Does anyone know what the Malaysian flag looks like?
I feel very bad for not knowing.
Right.
There you go.
Let's let's,
Let's go. So.
Each one of these things is a little prompt.
It has a kind of
some, some structure to it that is repeatable.
It kind of generates its own kind of script and then executes
a script based on what its inputs are.
And in this case, the inputs are whatever is pointing to the the component.
So write a newspaper article summarizing a championship game based on these rules
based on the rules for the game which was based on the text.
We also have, well, text and this shitty drawing that I drew,
which is leading us to to design a 3D model of the logo,
and we are still generating the newspaper
article which will be used to generate.
This is last time
leopards
roar to victory in inaugural across Tennis Championship.
This is awesome.
The rules of the game okay, cool.
Actually, this is much more complex and interesting than I thought.
Is anyone here Malaysian?
Is this a real.
Do you guys have tennis with different rules?
It would be interesting if it kind of came up with something
that was corresponded to reality.
Hey, that looks fun.
I would do this if you wanted to.
To remix this, all you would have to do is kind of change the input, right?
And then run those things again.
I really want to see the 3D national logo, but I don't think
it actually generated correctly.
So we're not doing bad for for demos.
So far so good.
Beginning of 2024,
we kind of had to ask ourselves, what do we actually kind of want from
from this?
Hey, yeah, I did get rid of it. What do we really want from the candidates?
Like where do we see this this going?
We done make real.
We done computer in these kind of, like,
associated things, you know, trying to cast imagination in the future.
Where do we think the canvas is going as a place to work with AI?
And part of that was just think about like, how do we use this?
Right? Like we use this primarily.
The killer feature of a canvas is collaboration, right?
I want to be able to work with other people on something very complex.
I want to be able to kind of have eight, ten, 15 people in the same document,
and for it to sort of have the affordances to, to accommodate for all that.
And the canvas really does that quite well.
You have your cursors flying around and things like that.
So why wouldn't we want to do that with with an AI as well?
Maybe that's the thing.
So we started on this really long journey of.
Of getting an
AI to see the canvas and to understand what's on the canvas
and also be able to act on the canvas.
So in the same way that I can create shapes and manipulate the canvas contents,
I wanted the AI to be able to do the same thing.
So let's say I have a cute drawing of a cat.
I'll add some ears.
But this is as far as I want to go.
I want to ask the agent to finish my cat.
So I think this was 2025,
so we tried to rip off cursors sidebar as it was in 2025.
Exactly.
And this really is a full kind of agent loop.
It's going to look it's kind of kind of
create stuff on the canvas.
It's going to kind of do a review and and there you go.
I can even reject or accept this.
That's wonderful.
Perfect, right.
I want to
let's make a little table here.
But of course, I'm not going to kind of tell the AI that this is a table
because it can see for itself, make the cat
go up on the table.
So the stuff that it made, this is not an image.
This is like the same stuff that I could make as well.
So it's it's kind of we're speaking the same language on the canvas.
Oh, God.
Each eye individually.
All right.
We're going.
It's not bad.
Actually.
These types of big moves is probably one of the things
that we've improved a lot in newer versions of this,
but it's reviewing its work.
Hopefully it doesn't say.
Let's see what it says.
Perfect.
Yeah. One 100.
Thank you.
Claude. Great.
That's all we want.
Right.
But it can be pretty good.
Let's see.
Add some more screens to my wireframes.
It's a much more complex one, but it's also more of like what
these image models are used to looking at and thinking about, which is, you know,
pictures of computer software and stuff like that.
So I'll let this cook for a second and, and talk about kind of where
we wanted to go next.
This was cool.
We had this harness not terribly good at moving cats around,
but it is pretty good at, for example, creating creating a UI on the canvas.
Definitely. This is cool.
But it was trapped in the sidebar, right?
We had like one instance of this, this agent trapped in the sidebar.
So from there, we we wanted to bring it onto the canvas
in the same way that like, you know, other users are on the canvas.
So that led us to.
To fairies.
To these guys.
So each one of these is an instance of that,
that harness that, that lives kind of on the canvas.
And while it started with just being like a way of visualizing the,
the agents number one, like just where are they?
Which ones exist, which one is which. Right.
You can kind of you can configure them
and change their hat
or because we needed two things like you can change the length of their legs.
I don't know if you can see that whatever you can, you can toss them around.
You can you can hold them.
They don't like that.
Yeah. Right on.
But you can talk to them as well.
Make a move as X and you can
you can visualize the state of the, the the agent as well.
So whether it's thinking or reviewing or working
cool.
Make a move as
oh and you can ask them to to do things.
And again it's pretty much the same harness as we,
we looked at with the whole cat on the table thing.
But there they can exist simultaneously.
They know about where each other are.
This is worse on live coding, by the way.
Let me, let me let me try this.
Maybe we can get them to work as a team.
So if I grab all three of them and I say play a full
game of tic tac toe.
Then they will operate as a unit.
One of them will be elected leader and will draft a plan.
Their wings will change colors to indicate that they're on the same team.
By the way, this is also collaborative.
You could have multiple people kind of sharing the same experience.
Coordinator comes up with a to do list and then delegates
those tasks to different fairies, different agents.
So first move and you can kind of read their Iasi chat as well.
First one is making a move there.
Wonderful. Second one.
Oh, this is going to be bad.
I'm skipping I'm bailing on this.
If if they do the same thing again.
Come on, come on. Demo
killing me the.
I think.
Oh, yeah.
All right, all right. Good good good times man.
They can also do much more complicated things,
taking an entire like PRD and turning it into wireframes.
Cleaning up your stuff actually is really cool.
One of my favorite parts about this, as I said, this is it's a collaborative,
so you can kind of share a link with other people.
And by the way, if you want to play with this, it's at fairies.
It's free.
You can spend my clawed tokens and whatever are they going to?
The cool thing is the reviewer, I believe, is
also looking to see whether someone's one or not.
They have tools to kind of like bail out on the on the generation.
But this is collaborative.
If I had ten other people working on this document with me
or in this experience with me, they would all have three fairies
each and my fairies would be able to see their fairies, and there's mine.
And while the orchestration is just within a single kind of users,
fairies having ten people on the same document, and we've done this,
having a collaborative experience on the same document together with.
30 fairies,
30 agents and and for that just to work for the UI and the application
to have affordances for not only human AI collaboration and human human
AI collaboration, but like so many at the same time,
did it recognize the win?
I bet it's just going to keep going.
Come on.
Pins and needles.
It's a super dramatic moment in AI development here.
Will it recognize the win?
Oh it's thinking.
Having.
All right.
Everyone wins.
Love it.
The having that kind of collaboration.
It's a joy I really encourage you to try because it kind of like all of these demos
should kind of point towards like a possibility
that maybe makes more sense
and a more narrow version of this experience that is
maybe tied to a specific type of user, like a product,
but it's very, very possible to do on the canvas with with Teodora.
So try it.
I'm going to end talking about one of the newest things
that we're doing with this same sort of,
I suppose, agent harness.
And that is a desktop app.
So we
want to have like an MCP like experience where you're able to,
to use in any agent to kind of work with the canvas.
Right.
Like I want to be able to say, hey, here's my code.
Can you just whip up a quick diagram of how this thing is working?
And then I want to be able to change the diagram
and say, okay, I've changed the way that this works in the diagram.
Can you bring that back to the code?
Update the code to match the changes that I made in the diagram.
That.
That that's cool.
I want I want that we have an MCP app for like cursor and cloud and things
where you can kind of do that thing, but it's still
it's still somewhat limited because it's kind of trapped inside of an application.
Some of my favorite AI applications right now are the ones that essentially
are desktop apps that allow you to communicate with the
the application using like a local MCP server.
So maybe paper pencil within the design space,
there's a lot of others, even just your normal.
I'd kind of works this way when you think about it.
And so we set up a desktop app that that does that right.
Has local MCP server.
And we could recreate that same sort of experience that,
you know, like from the ferries app or from the agent kind of sidebar starter
kit, which, by the way,
if you want to build with that, you can you can have all the code to do so.
But then we we kind of realized that we were looking at like code mode.
I don't know if you've
kind of tracked this, the idea that, well, actually
agents are just kind of better rather than making all these MCP calls,
if you just give them code and let them execute it
and then kind of generate the tool calls from there, but has like a runtime API,
you can say like editor dot, select all and it will select everything
on the canvas, that type of thing.
So since it was local, we're like, well, let's just give the the
AI direct access to to the editor and let's
see what it does with it. And
well, the answer is it does
incredibly crazy metaprogramming on top of the canvas.
So we started asking questions about how can you make this interactive?
Can we can you make this do stuff like, can you make the height of this
little circle affect the height of the guy?
Right.
And can we, can you make like, can you make these buttons actually work?
It kind of kind of back to make real but all operating within the canvas itself.
Now we don't have primitives for,
you know, when this is clicked,
do this when like you can you can.
We have enough of the low level stuff that you can find a way to program it.
And that's exactly what what Claude has done here is it's essentially
like script injecting the application in order to make these things work.
But we've we've given it a doorway to, to do that.
And again.
Silly example, but
like totally unexpected for us,
we we had a the first time we saw this, we were like,
hey, grab all the photos on our on my desktop,
put them into draw and give me like a search bar
that uses the native embeddings on Mac in order to like, filter the list.
And it just figured out a way to do it if you.
I don't think this will actually work, but
the code that it uses to do it is some of the
most insane.
Using Python to template JavaScript inside of a bash call.
Like the craziest, weirdest code that I've ever read in my life.
But it totally works.
And as a way of doing like kind of, you know, like ad hoc,
you know, like shoes,
I could do this and then say, you know,
where am I make the shoes work?
The only thing is that it's it's slow.
So I'm not going to I'm not going to wait here.
But that's,
that's basically the canvas.
That's basically some of the demos that we've I'm going to stop them
from walking the ways that we've used the canvas together with AI.
All of our demos are really, really broad and kind of pointless,
but we've seen customers in different teams kind of use
those same ideas and kind of narrow them, increase the quality
and make it really work for their users.
So hopefully I've
inspired someone in the room to take a shot at this.
If you do want to, you can go to
dev to use
the SDK, learn more about that,
or if you just need a free for your whiteboard that is at.
And that is that is my show.
I have time for some questions.
So thank you.
Wonderful.
Thank you Steve.
We probably have time for 1 or 2 very quick questions
because it's nearly lunchtime and I can hear your stomachs from here.
So grab Louie any hands up.
Hungry?
Hands up. Yeah. Lunch is on this way.
If you want to catch me later, I'll be around for for a couple hours.
Wonderful.
Thanks.
It is lunchtime now. Thanks again to Steve.
Big round of applause.
See you back here after lunch.